<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-03-17T01:19:15+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Flowtoolz</title><subtitle>Flowtoolz is about deep immersion in the present moment, about creating ultimate experiences through technology. We are in flow when building apps and other tools, and we want those tools to help you reach your own creative flow state.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Londonrealapp.com Is Finally Online</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/09/28/londonreal-app-new-website.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Londonrealapp.com Is Finally Online" /><published>2016-09-28T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2016-09-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2016/09/28/londonreal-app-new-website</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2016/09/28/londonreal-app-new-website.html">&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/blog-images/londonrealapp/11/poster.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; class=&quot;ft-shadow&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    Just a quick announcement: I'm so happy to release this new website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.londonrealapp.com&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Lononrealapp.com&lt;/a&gt;!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    A year after I started this project, it's finally coming full circle. Exciting times!
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Know Your Talents and Unleash Your Super Powers</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/09/23/how-to-know-your-talents-and-unleash-your-superpowers.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Know Your Talents and Unleash Your Super Powers" /><published>2016-09-23T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2016-09-23T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2016/09/23/how-to-know-your-talents-and-unleash-your-superpowers</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2016/09/23/how-to-know-your-talents-and-unleash-your-superpowers.html">&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/blog-images/self-development/how-to-know-your-talents/poster.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; class=&quot;ft-shadow&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;i&gt;
    Disclaimer: My dear reader, in this article, I talk directly to YOU. I may even ask you to do something. However, my point of view merely reflects my own life experience. I invite you put it on like a shoe. See if it fits and take it for what it's worth.
&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Know Thyself&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    What is the very first step of self-development or personal growth? Taking action? Setting goals? Finding a life purpose? Explicating values? I say it all begins with knowing yourself.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    You gotta know what you're dealing with before you start working on yourself. You want to choose a path that fits your personality and allows you to actualize everything you bring to the table.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Until here, that's all kind of obvious, right? Well, some of you will cringe as soon as we introduce a weirdly magical term: Talents.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    I guess some people in the self-development scene would like to think that they don't have any fixed predispositions and can change everything about them. I don't believe that for one second.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    If you can't think in terms of talents, you can't learn anything about your own talents, which means you can't really leverage your potential. In the following, you'll learn ...
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;What talents are and how they make a difference&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Why you might not know your own talents&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;What beliefs might prevent you from leveraging your talents&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;How you can objectively identify your talents by yourself&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Which personality tests help identifying talents and traits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;1. How Strength Focus Works&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    So let's clarify what we're talking about. Four amazing books inspired this article. Together they provide   a nice frame of reference:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/36072.The_7_Habits_of_Highly_Effective_People&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Stephen R. Covey - The 7 Habits of Highly Effective People&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/2477223.Managing_Oneself&quot; targt=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Peter F. Drucker - Managing Oneself&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/56452.Now_Discover_Your_Strengths&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Marcus Buckingham, Donald O. Clifton - Now, Discover Your Strengths&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/28012.Authentic_Happiness&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Martin E.P. Seligman - Authentic Happiness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Self-Awareness: Start Where You Are&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Covey's 7 step framework starts with what he calls &quot;proactivity&quot; which involves knowing where you are, i.e. &lt;i&gt;who&lt;/i&gt; you are:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &quot;We call it 'self-awareness' or the ability to think about your very thought process. This is the reason why man has dominion over all things in the world and why he can make significant advances from generation to generation.&quot;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Because talent analysis focuses on the centre of influence, fosters self-awareness and provides differentiated information about individual proactivity, it corresponds to Step 1 in Covey’s framework.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Self-Actualization: Leverage What You Are&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Self-awareness includes awareness of what you're really good at compared to other people. Buckingham &amp;amp; Clifton's book takes this a step further and explains why and how you should consciously focus on your personal strengths. The book is based on solid research and an enormous data set.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/blog-images/self-development/how-to-know-your-talents/book_cover.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;max-width:400px&quot; class=&quot;ft-shadow&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Buckingham &amp;amp; Clifton's work builds upon 3 basic assumptions. They may seem trivial. But most of the criticism the authors receive roots in a rejection or misunderstanding of their assumptions. Only as far as you understand and accept them, can you benefit from strength focus. So let's have a look at these assumptions:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Talents hardly change anymore after you've become an adult. We're talking about few basic talent themes. These are only slighly more concrete (differentiated) than the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Big_Five_personality_traits&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Big Five&lt;/a&gt;, which are known as being stable from age 30.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Strengths that build upon talents have the biggest potential for growth. We understand talent as a multiplier of learning effort: Talent × Invested Time = Strength. Of course, you can also significantly improve those skills which your talents don't support much. But the learning process would be slower and more frustrating there.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;To live a fulfilled life, you must live in accordance with your own personality, regardless of whether that personality came from nature or nurture. That's why it is so crucial that you can apply your talents in whatever you do everyday. So your job can never just be your job. What work you choose and how you approach it makes a huge difference for your well being and is the core challenge of lifestyle design.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The Hierarchy of Haves&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    While Maslow's &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maslow%27s_hierarchy_of_needs&quot;&gt;Hierarchy of Needs&lt;/a&gt; describes levels of what we want, I suggest there's also a &lt;i&gt;Hierarchy of Haves&lt;/i&gt; which describes the capabilities we use to get what we want: Deeply ingrained personality traits are the basis for talents which support strengths that help you excel at specific tools or professions:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/blog-images/self-development/how-to-know-your-talents/hierarchy_of_haves.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;max-width:400px&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    The higher up in the hierarchy the easier can you change that capability. You can't change your talents much as an adult, but you can still steer how you develop strengths and easily catch up on new tools and job roles. The basis for those decisions is knowing you're talents so you can get the most out of your strength development.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    In summary: &lt;b&gt;Talents&lt;/b&gt; are abstract personality traits that correspond to areas of great potential for personal development, specialisation, high performance and fulfilment. They root in your personality and psyche and they are quite stable over time. &lt;b&gt;Strengths&lt;/b&gt; are specific desirable abilities that can be trained. The level of a strength is a product of practice and underlying contributing talents.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;2. Why You Might Not Know Your Talents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    The enormous importance of actualizing talents is unquestionable. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parable_of_the_talents_or_minas#Parable_of_the_Talents&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Parable of the Talents&lt;/a&gt; (Matthew 25:14–30) suggests we should capitalize on what is given to us. In the parable, &quot;talent&quot; refers to a measurement unit of gold. Amazing how the meanings of &quot;talent&quot; and &quot;gift&quot; have expanded!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Your potential is given to you by a higher power. It is a gift. You can't know the purpose of that gift. You can only be grateful and put it into action. This down-to-earth approach to the meaning of life is deeply ingrained in our culture. But few people consciously follow it. Here are the 4 main reasons for why people don't make the most of their talents:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Beliefs set limits:&lt;/b&gt; Part of our cultural heritage is the belief that, in order to improve a system, you have to eradicate its weak points. The metaphor &quot;A chain is as strong as its weakest link&quot; seems obvious, and for technical systems it is often true.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Self-awareness is a paradox:&lt;/b&gt; How can the self know itself? That sounds logically impossible. And indeed, we all tend to have a distorted picture of ourselves and cannot clearly see the relative degrees to which our talents have developed. We pursue goals that aren't our own. We don't value our unique skills because they make it feel effortless. And yet, we constantly overestimate what we can do, as social psychology has shown.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Self-awareness hurts:&lt;/b&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;../where-focus-fails-and-how-all-rounders-get-shit-done&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;All-rounders&lt;/a&gt; in particular have a hard time facing the reality of unequal talents. You must be able to accept that some of your talents are weaker than others and that you can't change some aspects of your self, just as you can't decide to grow a third ear.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Letting go hurts:&lt;/b&gt; To use your strongest talents, you must say goodbye to all the other lifes you could live, the ones that build on talents which are just strong but not your strongest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;3. Two Beliefs that Hold Your Talents Hostage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    It's a cliche and it's true: &lt;i&gt;Inaccurate&lt;/i&gt; beliefs can totally sabotage your life and prevent you from being yourself. You will absolutely waste your talents if you never deal with conflicting beliefs that you possibly hold subconsciously. So let's look at the two most likely reservations you might have about strength focus.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&quot;My Weaknesses Limit What I can Achieve&quot;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Sure, you want to leverage those of your talents that compare best against other people. But what if you also secretely think that your weakest talents limit you anyway and that you should better work on them to avoid embarrassing yourself?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Let's have another look at the metaphor of the weakest link. In the context of traditional medicine, we might  apply that metaphor to the human body: We are &quot;healthy&quot; when all our bodily functions do their job. If one organ fails, we intervene and bring it back to a &quot;normal&quot; i.e. average state. In that reductive view, we are as healthy as our least healthy organ.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    So the &quot;weakest link model&quot; kind of works but it doesn't apply to what strength focus is about. It's not disease management but bio hacking. It's not about being average but about being everything you can be.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    If one strength is lacking, you can use others. But if no strength is really pronounced because you haven't aligned your strength and skill development with your talents, you can't shine or go into depth anywhere. Or look at it from the 80/20 angle: If you don't consciously build your skills on your talents, it'll take you much longer to develop the same skill level.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    So take a deep look at who you are, discover what works well, build on that, empower yourself with that, apply your strengths to more diverse tasks and thereby become who you're meant to be.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&quot;Focussing on Strengths Limits My Self-Expression&quot;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Knowing your talents and initiating growth through your strengths does &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; prevent you at all from being an &lt;a href=&quot;../where-focus-fails-and-how-all-rounders-get-shit-done&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;awesome all-rounder&lt;/a&gt;. That would just be another limiting belief.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Focussing on strengths is not specialization on certain tasks and does not restrict what you do, much less what you achieve. You can apply each strength to all kinds of tasks and goals. But utilizing your talents with such effectiveness requires you to know them.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    In fact, the main benefit of knowing your talents is that you can rethink and reshape the work you already do to align it with the way your mind and body literally &quot;work&quot;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Specializing on a job or role might help the economy or the system which defines that role. It doesn't necessarily help  &lt;i&gt;you&lt;/i&gt;. On the other hand, specializing on your strongest talents empowers yourself. It means you leverage your potential intelligently for whatever you wanna do.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;4. 12 Questions to Find Your Talents and Life Purpose&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    I mentioned why self-awareness is paradox and hurtful. You can't fully step out of yourself and compare yourself objectively. However, positive psychology and the self-development genre offer some questions you can ask yourself to objectively narrow down what you're good at and what your life purpose is.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
     I synthesized a list of questions from the most powerful ones I found. If you take just one thing away from this article, it should be this list. I warmly recommend that you print it out and work with it:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background-color:#eeffdd;padding:10px&quot; class=&quot;ft-shadow&quot;&gt;
    &lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;Questionaire to Identify Your Talents, Strengths and Life Purpose&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Quick learning: In which common learning processes do I skip steps?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Energy sources: Which activities energize me? When do I enter a flow state?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Longings: What are recurring themes in my life? What pulls me in and what do I attract?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Spontaneous decisions: How do I actually decide in day to day life without time to think?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;What did I want to do when I was 14 years old?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;What have strangers complimented me most on as a child?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;What did I grow up around? What strengths did my parents represent?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;What have I been doing in the last 10 years?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;What can I talk about effortlessly? Listening to myself, what subjects make me come alive?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;If I had all the money, love, physical and mental fitness I want, what would I do all day?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;What do I spend my money on beyond existential needs?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;What do my heroes and mentors do? What do I love about them?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
(1-4) Buckingham &amp;amp; Clifton discuss 4 indicators that can reveal your strongest talents. They call them the &quot;traces&quot; of talents.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
(5-9) &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.basicgrowth.com/the-67-steps-review/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Tai Lopez suggests&lt;/a&gt; 5 questions (also see &lt;a href=&quot;
    https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HQCK4UVbJIo&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Lg63A2aj8Go&amp;feature=youtu.be&amp;t=1h9m6s&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;) that show where your strengths are. He also wants you to identify the common themes, skills and practices. What is the intersection of your 5 answers?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
(10-12) I'm not sure where I picked these three up. But I'm convinced they are straight-forward ways to find out your true inclinations.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
&lt;p&gt;
Fragen aus peter drucker, managing oneself ... feedback analysis method
&lt;/p&gt;
--&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;5. How to Quantify your Super Powers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Personality&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Personality tests are only corny if you don't use them wisely. Your IQ and personality type can give you a good idea of where your areas of growth are. At least these classifications will make you think. If you disagree with a type description, that means you're reminded of what you already know about yourself in terms of personality type.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    IQ testing is a delicate matter. Don't do free online tests here. Only a registered psychologist can test you with a real IQ test that is standardized for your population. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mensa_International&quot;&gt;Mensa&lt;/a&gt; regularly conducts official IQ tests for relatively small fees. Maybe you find one in your area.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Compared to IQ testing, personality testing is more fuzzy anyway, so go and experiment. I recommend doing several free tests and averaging their results. Free MBTI tests are &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.humanmetrics.com/cgi-win/jtypes2.asp&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.16personalities.com/free-personality-test&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://psychcentral.com/quizzes/personality/start.php&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.my-personality-test.com/personality-type/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Free Big Five tests are &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.outofservice.com/bigfive/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.truity.com/test/big-five-personality-test&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.personalityassessor.com/bigfive/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://personality-testing.info/tests/IPIP-BFFM/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/blog-images/self-development/how-to-know-your-talents/big_five.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;max-width:600px&quot; class=&quot;ft-shadow&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    I did these kind of tests about a decade ago, so my real indicators might have changed a bit. The one Big Five test I did today (picture above) suggests I've become less neurotic, more extraverted and more agreeable. But to validate that result, I'd need to take several tests, just as I did back then.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Productive Talents&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    The first research question of Buckingham and Clifton was, which talents exist at all. The Gallup Institute interviewed &lt;b&gt;2 million people&lt;/b&gt; to answer that. The interviews have been analyzed with regards to talents, life satisfaction and success. In that sense, we understand them as &quot;productive talents&quot;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Using &lt;b&gt;factor analysis&lt;/b&gt;, they projected the talents that correlate with satisfaction and success onto &lt;a href=&quot;https://strengths.gallup.com/private/Resources/CSFTechnicalReport031005.pdf&quot;&gt;34 talent dimensions&lt;/a&gt;. These dimensions are relatively abstract. One dimension cannot be captured in a single defining term. Instead, it can only be described with texts and typical quotes of people who have this talent.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    The benefit of this approach is that the talents they identified are of equal degrees of abstraction and relevance and they're maximally independent (really distinct). To put it simply: These talent dimensions are more systematic and &lt;b&gt;closer to reality&lt;/b&gt; than our common language. Thereby they provide a vocabulary with which we can think about talents more rationally.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
You can measure the 34 talents for yourself with &lt;a href=&quot;http://strengths.gallup.com/110440/About-StrengthsFinder-20.aspx&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;StrengthsFinder 2.0&lt;/a&gt;. The quality of the results depends on the quality of your answers. You should answer honestly and spontaneously. These were my top five:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/blog-images/self-development/how-to-know-your-talents/sf_result.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;max-width:300px&quot; class=&quot;ft-shadow&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    I was surprised to be a strategist, let alone as my number one talent. After reading &quot;Now, Discover Your Strengths&quot;, I had predicted the other four of my top five talents. Along with my test results came a detailed report on how to apply my talents, which was a really interesting read.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Character Talents&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Values_in_Action_Inventory_of_Strengths&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;VIA IS&lt;/a&gt; lists 24 &quot;character strengths&quot;. Martin E.P. Seligman, one of the fathers of positive psychology, presents the ideas behind this classification in his book &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/28012.Authentic_Happiness&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Authentic Happiness&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/blog-images/self-development/how-to-know-your-talents/authentic_happiness.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;max-width:400px&quot; class=&quot;ft-shadow&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Although these traits are labelled &quot;strengths&quot;, we count them as &quot;character talents&quot; in the Hierarchy of Haves that we discussed above. In contrast to strengths, these character talents cannot be trained as well and are not applied to specific tasks. They count as talents because they are quite stable and general. Their main role is that you identify them so you can build upon- or work around them. These were my top 5:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Creativity, ingenuity, and originality&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Love of learning&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Judgment, critical thinking, and open-mindedness&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Curiosity and interest in the world&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Perspective (wisdom)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Oddly enough, these are exactly the traits ”that involve the acquisition and use of knowledge”. My character seem to be unbalanced or specialised, which is something the StrengthsFinder 2.0 also hinted at. But then again, I did the test long long ago.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Character talents differ from productive talents in two ways:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;They are less a means to an end and more a value in themselves. Good character traits are universally valued and directly induce happiness and meaning. They broadly effect many aspects of life.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;They can be trained a bit better since some of them respond well to meditation, for example: gratitude, optimism, loving kindness, compassion and self-regulation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
You also have five ”signature weaknesses”, character traits that scored lowest. Have an eye on them when you're in the trenches executing your process, so that they don't become handicaps. These were my weakest character traits:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Caution, prudence, and discretion&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Hope, optimism, and future-mindedness&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Self-control and self-regulation&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Gratitude&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Industry, diligence, and perseverance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Because character talents effect life more universally than productive talents, their lack should be managed less and compensated more. They seem to effect mental health and well-being more directly than productive talents.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Wrapping it Up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    If you never analyze your talents and strengths, chances are you're missing out on some low hanging fruits. Chance are you'll never be all you can be. Talents are a multiplier for all your efforts. Often, you just need to adjust &lt;i&gt;how&lt;/i&gt; you do something to leverage your full potential.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Confront the conflicting beliefs that possibly hold you back from embracing your strengths and use the presented questionaire and online tests to get an objective picture of your profile in terms of talents, strengths and personality.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Being aware of how your unique capabilities and inclinations effect your life, you will automatically make better decisions, and life will be easier in many ways. When you commit to a task, project or big goal, you will look for ways to put your strengths to work. Always ask yourself: Is there a way to achieve this result that is more aligned with how I function?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Building strengths and general skills takes time. Steer your skill development in a way that your talents and character traits support. Always have an eye on your least developed talents so you don't trip over them. Train character traits like gratitude and compassion if they are weak spots.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Start recognizing how good you are in certain areas and build your confidence with that. Trust in your superpowers, groom them and you will apply them in more and more ingenious ways, ultimately &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/where-focus-fails-and-how-all-rounders-get-shit-done&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;transcending their respective domains&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Disclaimer: My dear reader, in this article, I talk directly to YOU. I may even ask you to do something. However, my point of view merely reflects my own life experience. I invite you put it on like a shoe. See if it fits and take it for what it's worth.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Official London Real Apple TV App is Finally Here</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/09/17/the-official-londonrel-app-is-finally-here.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Official London Real Apple TV App is Finally Here" /><published>2016-09-17T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2016-09-17T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2016/09/17/the-official-londonrel-app-is-finally-here</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2016/09/17/the-official-londonrel-app-is-finally-here.html">&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/blog-images/londonrealapp/10/poster.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; class=&quot;ft-shadow&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    Almost a year ago, I started building the TV app for London Real. Since then, I invested hundreds of hours into this project. Now it's coming to a finish line.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Where We Are&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Previous versions of the app had some &lt;a href=&quot;../creating-the-london-real-apple-tv-app-9/&quot;&gt;technical issues&lt;/a&gt; which I could resolve over the last weeks. What we have now is a real &lt;a href=&quot;https://effectivesoftwaredesign.com/2014/11/02/the-minimum-viable-product-and-incremental-software-development/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;MVP&lt;/a&gt;, a product that is viable and minimal. It does just enough to provide value and it does it well. These are the latest improvements:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Streaming is completely reliable&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Video quality adjusts to bandwidth&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Feedback is accurate and responsive&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;All latest episodes are available&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Every episode has a description&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Several minor bugs are fixed&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Normally, the app pulls episode descriptions from Vimeo. But preprocessing existing descriptions and putting them into Vimeo is annoying manual work. The app does this automatically now. It processes descriptions from Youtube and uses them as fallback options.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/blog-images/londonrealapp/10/episode_list.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; class=&quot;ft-shadow&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    That process works as long as the structure of Youtube descriptions stays the same. For episodes where the structure deviates too much, clean descriptions can still be provided through Vimeo without releasing an app update.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Where We Go&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Aside from the &quot;track list&quot;, the app is still quite minimal. We could add countless amazing features in the future to turn it into a social fun educational platform. And trust me, we collected countless amazing ideas for that. So maybe this finish line will not be the last we ever take, but for now we have to close the current development cycle.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    The new version is waiting to be reviewed and accepted by Apple. Hopefully it hits the AppStore soon. Since we now have an MVP, we can create and execute a marketing campaign to gather feedback and establish the app as a part of the London Real eco system.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/blog-images/londonrealapp/10/itunes_connect.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; class=&quot;ft-shadow&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Since I started a new client job last week, I had to reduce my weekly time budget for the London Real app. In the following weeks, I'll spend that budget on promoting the app. After that, I'll evaluate this project and decide on next steps.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;How You can Contribute&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    To make the app really great we're &lt;a href=&quot;../creating-the-london-real-apple-tv-app-9/index.php#collaborators-wanted&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;looking for collaborators&lt;/a&gt; who can contribute chapter information for one or more episodes. About 30 episodes still lack that precious data which is required for the interactive table of contents that the app provides for every episode.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    App marketing is an exciting field and I greatly appreciate any tips on how to get the app to as many living rooms as possible. I'm not an expert and haven't even begun to brainstorm what options we have. Our audience are basically all Apple TV users.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Email us your requests, feedback or ideas. I will possibly give you access to our collaboration page where everything is explained in detail.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;margin-bottom:44px;margin-top:44px&quot;&gt;
    &lt;form action=&quot;mailto:app@londonrealacademy.com&quot;&gt;
        &lt;button type=&quot;submit&quot; value=&quot;Go to Google&quot;&gt;app@londonrealacademy.com&lt;/button&gt;
    &lt;/form&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;!-- https://www.thunderclap.it/projects/47271-have-50-great-mentors-now --&gt;
    You can also support the app by joining our &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thunderclap.it&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Thunderclap&lt;/a&gt;. Thereby you share a social media post together with all supporters at the same time. More details on that will follow soon.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/blog-images/londonrealapp/10/episode_details.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; class=&quot;ft-shadow&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Where Focus Fails and How All-Rounders Get Shit Done</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/09/09/where-focus-fails-and-how-all-rounders-get-shit-done.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Where Focus Fails and How All-Rounders Get Shit Done" /><published>2016-09-09T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2016-09-09T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2016/09/09/where-focus-fails-and-how-all-rounders-get-shit-done</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2016/09/09/where-focus-fails-and-how-all-rounders-get-shit-done.html">&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/blog-images/self-development/where-focus-fails-and-how-all-rounders-get-shit-done/poster.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; class=&quot;ft-shadow&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;i&gt;
Disclaimer: My dear reader, in this article, I talk directly to YOU. I may even ask you to do something. However, my point of view merely reflects my own life experience. I invite you put it on like a shoe. See if it fits and take it for what it's worth.
&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;You're Also Human? How Crazy is That?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Do you have many different things going on in your life? Do you seek out new challenges? Do you want to discover everything you are? Then I consider you an all-rounder like myself.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Creative people like entrepreneurs or artists are typical alrounders, as their work involves a bunch of different activities from ideation and creation over communication and collaboration to promotion and more. They don't just execute one craft all week. Instead they apply all kinds of skills to all kinds of projects using all kinds of tools and techniques.
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    This all-rounder lifestyle appeals to more and more people like us. We are fullfilled when we actualize our full potential. And the human potential is a wide spectrum. So we leave our 9 to 5 cubicle jobs behind, work on our own terms and explore what we're capable of. It's a quest to become a well rounded human being who lives in accordance with his own nature.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Not all projects we &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polymath&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;renaissance men and women&lt;/a&gt; do are paid jobs. Some of these endeavours mean working on our self, like losing weight. Others are pure self expression, like art and pet projects. And this self-development is about as important to us as any &quot;career&quot;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/blog-images/self-development/where-focus-fails-and-how-all-rounders-get-shit-done/awesome_all_rounder.png&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; class=&quot;ft-shadow&quot; style=&quot;max-width:400px&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    But doing lots of things and doing them on your own terms poses a huge challenge. You need to stay on top of all these projects and be productive in each of them, while nobody will tell you how to do that or when to do what. So the number one skill we have to master is self-management.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Some all-rounders pride themselves on being flexible enough to handle everything that comes up. They just broke out of a rigid environment and now want to experience flow and listen to their intuition. I think this notion employs multiple dangerous misunderstandings. For instance, by committing yourself to everything at once you don't commit yourself at all.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Being free means you must pick your own restrictions. In the following, I'll deduct how implementing the right kind of restrictions enables all-rounders to be highly productive across many different domains.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;About the F Word&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    A major part of the self-development scene has picked &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/17349126-focus&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;focus as their mantra&lt;/a&gt;. Focus on your vision, your goal, your task at hand! Do &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/16256798-the-one-thing&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;just one thing&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/18595404-the-power-of-no&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;say &lt;i&gt;No&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to all others! As a result, &quot;Focus&quot; has become a meaningless, problematic, even dangerous term. I'll explain.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Focussing on one goal works well for people who want to achieve elite excellence in one craft or get rich in a traditional industry that thrives on the law of comparative advantages and rewards high specialization.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    A good example of this philosophy is Dan Pena, who says the best advice he ever got is &quot;Focus on the few, not the many!&quot; Dan focused his life on making money and teaching others how to be super successful.
&lt;/p&gt;
    But what about prototypical all-rounders like &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joe_Rogan&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Joe Rogan&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/368593.The_4_Hour_Workweek&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Tim Ferriss&lt;/a&gt;? They pursue lots of different adventures. Tim Ferriss is famous for applying the pareto principle to everything, and he showed that with only 20% of the time you can still reach 80% of the skill level. Now, 80% is not elite excellence but enough to have fun and be happy.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    How do people like Joe and Tim get so much done when they don't focus on just one goal? I think they actually do focus very intensely, on one goal at a time. They just don't settle on a specific life goal, avoiding &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Big_Design_Up_Front&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;big design up front&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Successful all-rounders employ different adventures as milestones within their bigger journey. They dive into each project completely but also don't get lost in it. They define meaningful goals that are also achieveable. And they don't commit to projects with totally unknown outcomes or timeframes. You could say they live their life as an &lt;a href=&quot;../agilemind/index.php&quot;&gt;agile iterative process&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    The other critical self-management skill that successful all-rounders have is to manage multiple parallel projects or ongoing tasks. In that regard, business men like Dan Pena have always been all-rounders.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Keep it Flowy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    To be able to run several projects in parallel, you must be able to concentrate on the task at hand. So focus is crucial on the micro time scale as well. Not only do we know that mono-tasking is superior to multi-tasking, but deep concentration also promotes &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/66354.Flow&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;flow&lt;/a&gt; and creativity.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Flow is extremely important to me personally. For years, I assumed that shutting out all distractions is the key to that. I thought the longer I can work on one thing uninterrupted the better, and the best way to do a project would be to do only that project until it's done.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    One consequence was that I never made real progress on my goal to pick some of my songs and produce an album. That project requires a few months, and I was never able or willing to take a break and invest the time. Sometimes I took one or two weeks and worked on one isolated song. I really dived into it. But at the end, I was totally exhausted and estranged from regular life.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Trying to sustain focus by avoiding any concurring projects is problematic:
    &lt;ol&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;You drain out.&lt;/b&gt; Productivity and creativity evaporate. You need lots of breaks in between and long recovery after projetcs. A big part of this kind of breaks is unnecessary as we'll see during this article.&lt;/li&gt;

        &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;You get attached to what drains you out.&lt;/b&gt; You can't let go of the task, can't get out of the flow tunnel. You tend to indulge in the task and make it your comfort zone. You have no concept or idea of what comes afterwards. You lose sight of the big picture. You have no time slot for recurring tasks that need to be handled on a regular basis.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;P&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; - The Panorama Productivity Principle&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Capacity Cycles&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
     Different human capacities are more or less independent. For instance, athletes cycle through different physical capacities to maximize the overall output of their training. When their muscles recover they can still train cardio. When their cardiovascular system recovers they can still challenge their nervous system by practicing technique. When their concentration starts to fade, they can return to strengthening their muscles.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
In the end, our brain is part of our body and its different areas have different responsibilities. So it's no wonder that we also have distinct mental capacities. Those are modes in which the brain processes information: mathematical, social, creative, analytic, aesthetic, verbal, logical, visual etc.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    These modes are somehow independent. For instance, after I'm exhausted from writing program code, writing an essay feels refreshing. When I can't concentrate on writing anymore, I can perfectly discuss the same subject with a friend.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    To maximize your overall productivity you must cycle through the right set of tasks/projects and focus on each one the right amount of time. Before you're too exhausted, you end the working session and switch to a different task. Every switch gives you a fresh start.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    A task typically relies on multiple capacities to varying degrees. Using a specific tool is kind of a capacity and can be tiring. Just switching to a different tool can give you a break while your outcome and productivity remain stable. So by cycling through varying capacities, you need much less breaks overall, but that's not everything.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Session Length&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Let's look at these working sessions more closely:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/blog-images/self-development/where-focus-fails-and-how-all-rounders-get-shit-done/Chart.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; class=&quot;ft-shadow&quot; style=&quot;max-width:400px&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    When you switch to a fresh (recovered, reloaded) capacity, your &lt;font style=&quot;background-color:#ffc0c0&quot;&gt;current productivity or speed (output per hour)&lt;/font&gt; starts at zero. You first need to get into it, just as you warm up before an athletic performance. When you find your orientation and rhythm, &lt;font style=&quot;background-color:#ffc0c0&quot;&gt;productivity&lt;/font&gt; surges up. It reaches a maximum and later drops off due to exhaustion of the exploited capacity.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    You maximize your total productivity across everything you do by maximizing the &lt;font style=&quot;background-color:#c0ffc0&quot;&gt;overall (average) productivity of each session&lt;/font&gt;. Since the &lt;font style=&quot;background-color:#ffc0c0&quot;&gt;current productivity&lt;/font&gt; rises and falls during a session, the &lt;font style=&quot;background-color:#c0ffc0&quot;&gt;session average&lt;/font&gt; does so as well. When a &lt;font style=&quot;background-color:#c0ffc0&quot;&gt;session's average productivity&lt;/font&gt; is at its maximum, you need to stop the session and start the next.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
It's that moment when you know you're a bit exhausted and have clearly slowed down, but you're still quick enough to get some more things done: Don't force it! Stop, have a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pomodoro_Technique&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;short break&lt;/a&gt; and continue with a task that draws on different capacities of yours!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Number of Projects&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    How many different tasks and projects should you have in rotation? Just as many as you personally need to maintain a healthy &quot;capacity cycle&quot;. Any more than that would needlessly scatter your efforts and reduce the frequency in which you can deliver meaningful results.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    But we can narrow that down further: It is probably not optimal to have 2 sessions of the same task at any one day. The involved capacities most likely do not recover fully until the next day. Also, you surely have enough projects or ongoing tasks to be able to avoid these repetitions.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    But then, a night of sleep likely reloads most of your systems. So it's also not optimal to have much more going on than what you could get through in a day.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    So if you plan for 8 working hours a day and an average session length of 1.5 hours, you can take on 5 to 6 projects or categories of tasks. My typical session length is one hour. So I have 8-9 things going (including morning routine and exercise), and I get through all of them almost every day.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/blog-images/self-development/where-focus-fails-and-how-all-rounders-get-shit-done/cards.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;How to Achieve Panorama Productivity&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Rapid Iteration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Running multiple projects in parallel requires that you follow a radical iterative process in each project. Plan to deliver small but valuable results in short iterations. I treat every week as an iteration. On Sundays and for every project, I define a small tangible result that I want to produce until next Sunday. Of course, I also review what I achieved last week and adjust my plans accordingly.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    The best kind of result allows you to gather feedback. Remember: As an all-rounder you do all these projects as explorative experiments. You have to be aware of how the experiment itself is going. What's the return on investment of this project? Does it bring you money, relationships, happyness? Do the results resonate with you and others? That's another reason to review and plan between iterations.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Time Boxing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The idea of &quot;Panorama Productivity&quot; as I presented it has direct implications on what an optimal schedule would be. It lets you do your sessions regularly and distributes work loads evenly over the available days. It is automatically sustainable and does not need regular slacking days.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
But most of all, an optimal schedule implies radical time boxing. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.entrepreneur.com/article/275718&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Forget To-Do lists&lt;/a&gt;, forget even your calendar. Create an iteration schedule with time boxes for all your sessions, so they cycle through your different capacities, projects or task categories. This is my recent week schedule template:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/blog-images/self-development/where-focus-fails-and-how-all-rounders-get-shit-done/week_schedule.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; class=&quot;ft-shadow&quot; style=&quot;max-width:600px&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Enforce time boxing like a savage. Within your time boxes and projects you can, of course, use to-do lists and regular task management techniques. Then in your iteration review, you adjust factors like the weighting between projects and the individual session lengths.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Knowing there's a time slot for everything enables you to focus on the task or project at hand. And a schedule of this type  also helps you shield your precious hours against the big wormholes that normally suck your time in, like other people who don't understand what a &quot;home office&quot; is.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Sleep&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    An optimal schedule also timeboxes sleep: There's an average number of hours that you sleep everyday. By timeboxing that amount of sleep and forcing yourself to go to bed and get up at the same times every day, you give your body its inner clock back.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    After a while, you won't even need an alarm anymore. Your body will know when it's time to wake up. It will also know when it's time to sleep, and that will get you more recovery out of the same amount of sleep. Sleep is the foundation of your productivity rhythm. Guard it like your life!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Mindfulness&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    The biggest challenge of this radical time boxing is actually not getting into flow but getting out of it. Being able to let go of an ongoing task and shift your attention to the next one is just as important as being able to focus your attention on the current task.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Both of these processes rely on your ability to manage your attention, which you can improve through mindfulness meditation. So switching focus has nothing to do with multitasking. It is part of the idea of focus itself.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Inspiring Role Models&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    The perverted degree of specialization and the price that we pay for it are largely a phenomenon of &quot;modern&quot; society. So, to know that guys like Tim Ferriss and Joe Rogan &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; extremely successful as all-rounders even in today's world inspires me like nothing else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    And if you look back in history, you'll find even more inspiring well-rounded generalists. One of the most eye opening books on productivity I ever read is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/15799151-daily-rituals&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Daily Rituals: How Artists Work&lt;/a&gt;. It's a collection of what we know about the daily work routines of hundreds of the greatest minds of all time, from Einstein over Picasso to Freud.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    After reading these numerous accounts, two things became very clear to me: First, high performing all-rounders are mostly crazy people and represent a wide range of pronounced personalities. Second, a few characteristics are almost universal among them. These characteristics relate to the very work that made them famous and can be boiled down into 4 rules:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Put work &lt;b&gt;first&lt;/b&gt;. Do whatever is necessary to have the time and silence your work requires.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Establish regularity and routines. If you need exceptions, you better rework your routines.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Get up early and do the the primary, most challenging work after getting up.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Plan for only 3 to 4 hours of concentrated work per day, but take &lt;b&gt;no&lt;/b&gt; day off.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    In summary, focus does not mean pursuing just one goal or doing the same work all the time. It can help you live all different sides of yourself and thereby realize your full potential.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    The principle of capacity cycles makes it very clear how all-rounders can stay on top of all their endeavours. Radically time boxing your different adventures and taking them on in an agile iterative fashion can actually set you free to discover what you're here for. It will make you ultra productive across a range of domains, so you can be a real sophisticate, a renaissance man (or woman) who lives this human life to the fullest.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
These books were referenced in this article, ordered by my personal preference:
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/368593.The_4_Hour_Workweek&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;The 4-Hour Workweek&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/15799151-daily-rituals&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Daily Rituals: How Artists Work&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/18595404-the-power-of-no&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;The Power of No&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/66354.Flow&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Flow: The Psychology of Optimal Experience&lt;/a&gt;

    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/17349126-focus&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Focus: The Hidden Driver of Excellence&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/16256798-the-one-thing&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;The One Thing: The Surprisingly Simple Truth Behind Extraordinary Results&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Disclaimer: My dear reader, in this article, I talk directly to YOU. I may even ask you to do something. However, my point of view merely reflects my own life experience. I invite you put it on like a shoe. See if it fits and take it for what it's worth.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Where’s the London Real Apple TV App Going?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/09/07/where-is-the-londonreal-app-going.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Where's the London Real Apple TV App Going?" /><published>2016-09-07T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2016-09-07T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2016/09/07/where-is-the-londonreal-app-going</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2016/09/07/where-is-the-londonreal-app-going.html">&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/blog-images/londonrealapp/9/poster.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; class=&quot;ft-shadow&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Hello Back&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    I know I've been silent for a while. Here's why: Since releasing the app at the beginning of this year, I was in the London Real Business Accelerator and handled 2 other client projects. The last project ended recently and the next is gonna kick off in 2 days.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    But in the last 9 days I squeezed out some time for the London Real app. The app now includes the latest episodes, a description for every episode and new chapter information for some episodes. However, what took the most time was to migrate the app to the latest versions of Cocoapods, Xcode, Swift, tvOS, PureLayout, Alamofire and other technical dependencies.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;collaborators-wanted&quot;&gt;Text Talents Wanted!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    One of the great features of the app is that users can navigate an episode through a table of contents or &quot;track list&quot;. Unfortunately, generating meaningful timestamps and titles for the chapters requires some time and effort. Currently, I don't have the time to do that. But I'm sure the community which is the London Real Academy could crowd source a solution.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    The challenge of extracting chapters is that they should be meaningful and helpful to the user. Any chapter should be a few minutes long, like 3 to 10, and its title should &lt;b&gt;summarize&lt;/b&gt; the theme or subject that is being dicussed during this chunk of time. Ideally, the title also pops like good copywriting.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Whoever does the work must be able to read between the lines, recognize themes and summarize them in her own words. Just quoting some line from the interview guest doesn't do it in most cases.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Creating the chapters for an episode typically takes at least as much time as the duration of the episode itself. One cannot wind forward but must listen closely. That's what makes this feature valuable but also expensive.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Road Ahead&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    The other issue that still needs to be resolved is the video streaming itself. It is still unreliable and doesn't provide sufficient feedback to the user. This is due to the limitations of the technology that I chose in the beginning. In the next one or two weeks, I will explore and test other technical options.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    I'd also be open to collaborate with developers from the London Real Academy. Sometimes, just being able to talk and bounce ideas around could help me see possible solutions to technical challenges like the one I mentioned. So if you are a LRA member and a developer of some kind and want to be part of this piece of London Real, feel free to contact me.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    I plan to turn this app into an app framework for tvOS, so that I can offer similar apps to other video content producers. The London Real TV app is gonna benefit greatly from this process. So any feedback and collaboration from the community helps promote London Real and grow the community itself.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Hello Back I know I've been silent for a while. Here's why: Since releasing the app at the beginning of this year, I was in the London Real Business Accelerator and handled 2 other client projects. The last project ended recently and the next is gonna kick off in 2 days. But in the last 9 days I squeezed out some time for the London Real app. The app now includes the latest episodes, a description for every episode and new chapter information for some episodes. However, what took the most time was to migrate the app to the latest versions of Cocoapods, Xcode, Swift, tvOS, PureLayout, Alamofire and other technical dependencies. Text Talents Wanted! One of the great features of the app is that users can navigate an episode through a table of contents or &quot;track list&quot;. Unfortunately, generating meaningful timestamps and titles for the chapters requires some time and effort. Currently, I don't have the time to do that. But I'm sure the community which is the London Real Academy could crowd source a solution. The challenge of extracting chapters is that they should be meaningful and helpful to the user. Any chapter should be a few minutes long, like 3 to 10, and its title should summarize the theme or subject that is being dicussed during this chunk of time. Ideally, the title also pops like good copywriting. Whoever does the work must be able to read between the lines, recognize themes and summarize them in her own words. Just quoting some line from the interview guest doesn't do it in most cases. Creating the chapters for an episode typically takes at least as much time as the duration of the episode itself. One cannot wind forward but must listen closely. That's what makes this feature valuable but also expensive. The Road Ahead The other issue that still needs to be resolved is the video streaming itself. It is still unreliable and doesn't provide sufficient feedback to the user. This is due to the limitations of the technology that I chose in the beginning. In the next one or two weeks, I will explore and test other technical options. I'd also be open to collaborate with developers from the London Real Academy. Sometimes, just being able to talk and bounce ideas around could help me see possible solutions to technical challenges like the one I mentioned. So if you are a LRA member and a developer of some kind and want to be part of this piece of London Real, feel free to contact me. I plan to turn this app into an app framework for tvOS, so that I can offer similar apps to other video content producers. The London Real TV app is gonna benefit greatly from this process. So any feedback and collaboration from the community helps promote London Real and grow the community itself.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What If Your Unconscious Negates Self Development?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/09/04/what-if-your-unconscious-negates-self-development.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What If Your Unconscious Negates Self Development?" /><published>2016-09-04T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2016-09-04T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2016/09/04/what-if-your-unconscious-negates-self-development</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2016/09/04/what-if-your-unconscious-negates-self-development.html">&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/blog-images/self-development/what-if-your-unconscious-negates-self-development/poster.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; class=&quot;ft-shadow&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;i&gt;
        Disclaimer: My dear reader, in this article, I talk directly to YOU. I may even ask you to do something. However, my point of view merely reflects my own life experience. I invite you put it on like a shoe. See if it fits and take it for what it's worth.
    &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Self Transformation and the Limits of Technique&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
There where times in my life when I felt like a sports car without a spark plug. Everything was in position, everything was optimized, the gas tank was full. But I couldn't get started. It was a nightmare.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
For instance, whenever I sat down to work on my master thesis, all lights went out. It took abnormal amounts of energy out of my system. It wasn't enough to just get over some threshold and get started. The whole time, it felt like putting the pedal to the metal while the emergency brake is put on. So exhausting. Unbearable.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why did that task suck the life out of me? Because it was linked to fears. All that life hacking doesn't do much, when you're blocked by your subconscious mind. Most of what I did back then to develop myself was just technique, just optimization of marginal conditions. But the biggest challenge in growing as a person and achieving your goals is to overcome deep seated fears.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The glasses through which we see the world can produce a very disadvantageous picture. A picture that scares the shit out of you without you even realizing that you're scared. Scared that everything goes wrong, scared not to be enough, scared not to live your full potential, scared to choke on being detached from yourself.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;How to Treat a Sabotaging Brain&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
There is a booming industry of superficial self development that can suck you in and distract you from what you actually need to do. Real transformation cannot be sold, and certainly not as a dehumanized digital product.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The brain has no simple switch that you can just turn on, no spark to ignite and release your potential, no magic trick. Don't expect that. Don't search for that. The mentality of &quot;Just fucking do it!&quot; is useful and works for a moment. But it costs will power, and sooner or later, the reality of who you are at your core will have its way, no matter what self development techniques you apply to cover that up.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Unconscious fears and harmful patterns of thought and perception root in past experiences and are deeply ingrained in your nervous system. Of course, you can intentionally change the structure of your brain. But &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/2004272.Biologie_der_Angst&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;reversing such fundamental traits takes time&lt;/a&gt;. You need to recondition your brain by overwriting its old program with a more useful one. This will only work if the process meets 3 requirements:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Think long term and practice patience and perseverance.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Start with small steps and slowly increase the challenge from there.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Utilize emotions with whatever practice you apply.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Point 3 is of particular importance. Embodiment and excitement are necessary ingredients in reprogramming the subconscious mind.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Hero's Journey as a Mental Training Protocol&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/588138.The_Hero_With_a_Thousand_Faces&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; that coined the term &quot;Hero's Journey&quot; had changed my life long before I heard business people talking about it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/blog-images/self-development/what-if-your-unconscious-negates-self-development/journey.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; class=&quot;ft-shadow&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The basic 5 step process of training your brain to overcome fear is closely related:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Acknowledge the fear, accept it, feel it.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Identify an obstacle that triggers the fear. This should be neither too small nor too large. Like in physical training, the stimulus should cause the system to adapt but not overwhelm it.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;As Tai Lopez preaches: Lead with reward. Define it, visualize it. Imagine how it would feel to have overcome the obstacle.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Here's where Dan Pena comes in: Just fucking do it!&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Enjoy the reward. Celebrate your success. Savour all the positive feelings that come up. Relive the emotional journey you've just been through over and over again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The crucial factor here is that you do it &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Practice_(learning_method)#Deliberate_practice&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;deliberately&lt;/a&gt;. One way or another, life forces you to go through this process countless times. But to improve your habits of thought and behaviour, you need to go through this with intention and awareness. Seek out opportunities to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/18668059-the-obstacle-is-the-way&quot;&gt;turn obstacles into positive experiences&lt;/a&gt;. Concentrate on every of the 5 steps. Feel it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
What you actually achieve by overcoming the obstacle is not that important. It can be a very small thing. The purpose of this practice is not to achieve specific results but to redefine how your subconscious mind generally reacts to obstacles. When a challenge presents itself, you'll get butterflies in your stomach. Confidence, curiosity, playfulness and the joy of anticipation will flood your body. You will not freeze but attack.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Real Growth Every Day&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
There are many ways to weave this process into your life. A good start is to recognize little everyday obstacles and turn them into little positive experiences. You can also &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/20567918-mini-habits&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;use such mini obstacles to establish good habits&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
One practice that I do every day is this: Every morning, I think of a (sometimes really small) obstacle that I overcame the day before. I focus on the positive aspects of how I felt afterwards and embrace that emotion for a moment.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
You can extend that practice to big obstacles in the distant past or turn it into a long formal meditation. Even any regular meditation practice can help. It promotes self-awareness and can loosen you up so you're more playful and open to experiment:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Meditation can help you recognize immediately when you start to procrastinate  out of fear.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Meditation can sharpen your perception of what exactly triggers your fears.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Meditation can make you more aware of what kind of success induces positive emotions.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Meditation can dissolve your sense of self and your identification with what you have or do.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Meditation can free you from the pressure of your own expectations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/blog-images/self-development/what-if-your-unconscious-negates-self-development/zen.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; class=&quot;ft-shadow&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    You can also use the process to prepare yourself for the obstacles ahead. I personally have come to perceive bigger projects through the same lense. I employ it in techniques like priming, planning, visualization and journaling.  I prepare a reward and take the time to go through all the steps.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Become a detective of your own fears and see them as opportunities for deliberate practice. Plan and setup your positive experiences so they can change who you are!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Further Reading&lt;/h2&gt;

Here are 5 interesting related books. As mentioned, the first one was life changing for me. The second one inspired this article:
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/588138.The_Hero_With_a_Thousand_Faces&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;The Hero With a Thousand Faces&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;(Hero's Journey)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/2004272.Biologie_der_Angst&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Biologie der Angst - Wie aus Stress Grefühle werden&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt; (Meaning: &quot;The Biology of Fear - How Stress turns into Emotions&quot;)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/18668059-the-obstacle-is-the-way&quot;&gt;The Obstacle Is the Way: The Timeless Art of Turning Trials into Triumph&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/20567918-mini-habits&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Mini Habits: Smaller Habits, Bigger Results&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/21841140-discovering-your-soul-signature&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Discovering Your Soul Signature: A 33-Day Path to Purpose, Passion &amp;amp; Joy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">7 Lessons from the London Real Business Accelerator</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/05/15/london-real-business-accelerator.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="7 Lessons from the London Real Business Accelerator" /><published>2016-05-15T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2016-05-15T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2016/05/15/london-real-business-accelerator</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2016/05/15/london-real-business-accelerator.html">&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/blog-images/self-development/london-real-business-accelerator/poster.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; class=&quot;ft-shadow&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On &lt;b&gt;December 17&lt;/b&gt; last year, I was accepted into the &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://londonrealacademy.com&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;London Real&lt;/a&gt; Business Accelerator&lt;/b&gt; (in the following just &quot;Bizacc&quot;). Brian Rose and his crew made sure that the 10 people who where chosen from 200+ applications felt quite proud of themselves. Above all, Brian is a communicator. And therein, I also found the first teaching on how to run a business. The email reads:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;However we are &lt;b&gt;oversubscribed&lt;/b&gt; and I can only accept the first members to make the final payment in full. To lock in your spot click here (you have until December 20th).&quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice the date and let that sink in. If you feel alienated by this, the Bizacc might not be for you. &lt;b&gt;But&lt;/b&gt; if you just acknowledge that the Bizacc is a business itself, you can learn even more from it. So I read that statement as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Depict yourself as being in high demand.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Depict your customer as a VIP.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Get the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YjcIRQuCXr0&quot;&gt;fucking money&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, I gather some thoughts and feelings about the Bizacc. Now, more than two months after the program ended, I can say I learned a lot from it, although some of my conclusions go beyond its curriculum or even challenge it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I dive into the 7 lessons I (re-)learned, let's look at the Bizacc itself and whether you should apply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Course Structure&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of the curriculum. We did one &quot;module&quot; every week. There was an introductory module in the beginning, the expected 8 week program and a bonus module at the end. So we had 10 modules:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Pitch Yourself (Intro)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Find Your Micro Niche&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Create Your Product&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Build Your Website&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Develop Your Social Media Presence&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Market Your Product&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sell Your Product&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Harness Your Network&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Optimise Your Funnel&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Build Your Product Eco System (Bonus)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every Module was accompanied by a Video in which Brian laid out the respective intent, ideas and tools. The videos serve their purpose very well and communicate a consistent thought framework and anchor for the whole accelerator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brian does a phenomenal job and his presentation alone is inspiring. Those videos are a treasure, and I hope they keep them up, so I can get back to them years from now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every Module was also accompanied by a &quot;workbook&quot; which basically was a template for the homework we had to do every week. We posted the results in a private Facebook group, where we also kept in touch with the pack.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Live Calls&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twice a week, we had live calls via &lt;a href=&quot;http://zoom.us&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Zoom&lt;/a&gt;. A &quot;keynote call&quot; on Tuesdays and a &quot;workshop call&quot; on Sundays. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the keynote call, Brian repeated this week's module content and generally reflected on how we're doing. He also briefly checked in with each of us, so everyone would give their 3 minute update. The workshop call was more open to our questions, specifically about the current week's homework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bizacc group size was advertised as being 5 but ended up at 10. There are pros and cons to that. Getting to know the other participants, their way of thinking and their struggles was an essential part of the learning experience and made the workshop calls interesting. On the other hand I feel a more consistent group of 5 people would have added value in other ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was only little 1on1 coaching with Brian and the team. We were supposed to have 2 or three such calls with Brian, each 5-7 minutes. We could also schedule individual calls with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/profile.php?id=100008442845483&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Fritz&lt;/a&gt;. I had a a quite valuable 30min talk with him. If you would like more individual coaching, you might wanna consider how many hours of 1on1 coaching you'd get for the price of the Bizacc from a locally available startup- or business consultant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Who should Apply?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really liked the medium (videos, live calls, group) of the Bizacc, now what about the message? Should you apply? I feel that wasn't obvious from London Real's marketing. The Accelerator applies to a more specific target group than you might think. Good for you if you're in that group. Less so if you're not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of what we did relates to &lt;i&gt;inbound marketing&lt;/i&gt;. And although that's an important part of London Real as a business, London Real means so much more to members of the London Real Academy. And of course, you need to be a member to apply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'd argue that the relevance of inbound marketing depends on your kind of business. To be more precise: The Accelerator aims predominantly at &lt;i&gt;personal online lifestyle businesses&lt;/i&gt;. I can only guess what I mean by that, but you get the point ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What business development stages does the Bizacc cover? First of all, it covers more than the 8 weeks it lasts. As Brian said: &quot;We make you drink from the fire hose.&quot; You'll learn tools that you can apply over and over again for different products and the rest of your life, starting with how a product relates to your personal story and ending with optimising the sales funnel of your online business which offers a whole product eco system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sounds like a lot, eh? Well it is and it isn't. You get a big thought framework but no details. You might already possess 90% of the attitude and knowledge that the Bizacc delivers. Don't expect rocket science. You get the most out of it if you have a) a strong vision and b) enough time (money) on your hand to immediately apply the Accelerator to your vision. Plan for 20 hours per week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can be argued that the most important phase of turning your passion into a business comes even before knowing what that passion is and what that business should look like. And although the Accelerator touches on that, it would be a pretty good idea before you apply to have a pretty good idea of where you want to go. If you really need a life coach or don't have a strong vision, this 8 week program will fly by and you'll miss out on what it offers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My personal and highly subjective experience was that I wished the Accelerator had dwelled on that vision more, question it harder, reveal what options I actually have and guide me in those foundational decisions. After all I want to pursue my idea for the right reasons. The first module addressed that, but to really address it for myself, I felt I would have needed more time, more critical feedback and more actual 1on1 consulting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, I received an important message on that. So let's look at what I learned...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;1. Just Fucking do it&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're a diverse allrounder overflowing with ideas, you need to draw a line at some point and go for it. Self analysis is the worst kind of paralysis. You'll discover what works by doing stuff. You'll discover what you're passionate about by doing stuff. And all that might take 8 years, so don't expect it in 8 weeks but rather use that time to get going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd stretch that conclusion further: We all search for magic bullets in one way or another. We need rules to hold on to. More than enough businesses are ready to sell us what we think we need, and there even is a time for that in the journey of each of us. But be honest with yourself: Where are you on your journey? Still looking for magic bullets?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The realisation that you actually don't need anything is as liberating as it is painful. If you want to transform your life and yourself, no one can go through the necessary passages for you.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the one thing you won't learn in the Bizacc is that you might be better off without it. Your impulse to apply might just be an impulse to procrastinate. Why not do some real shit and fail? Why not apply what you already know? Why not follow your intuition, since it feeds off all the London Real episodes you watched for entertainment? WWDPS? Well he would certainly say: Conventional wisdom is almost always wrong, so just fucking do it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;2. Don't just set Goals, Create Options&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goals are there to get you going, not to achieve them. They provide orientation like the north star. Don't cling to your goals or even to your plans on how to get there. If you fall in love with your grand vision, you might miss what actually is there, right now, right where you are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;So keep your eyes open and take advantage of the people and opportunities that come across your way. You cannot plan everything out, but you can reframe every situation. It's amazing how much you get when you let go just a little. You will see doors open where previously were guard rails.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;3. Generate Value, not Revenue&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Online businesses have become such a cliche. Everyone has one. Nowadays, customers smell the related inbound marketing techniques from a mile anyway. And they don't want to be sold. I'm just saying it's not getting easier. So don't be another online business. Dare to be yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Focus on helping people and don't be selly. For instance, look at &lt;a href=&quot;http://combatsportslaw.com&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;combatsportslaw.com&lt;/a&gt;. That site has one little call to action on the bottom right. Everything else is content. The guy is certainly a KPI in MMA legal issues. He does it like Mimi Ikonn advised in her London Real interview:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;Provide value, make the product available. If people need to buy it, they will make that decision. You don't need to sell it to them.&quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;4. Don't just be Yourself but be just Yourself&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;London Realers have one or two things in common. For example, we want to translate our passion into fulfilling and rewarding work. And as Brian said after the first week, the London Real Business Accelerator is actually a &quot;Life Accelerator.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started the Bizacc by pitching ourselves and telling your own stories. As preparation, that makes sense. Let me paraphrase Oren Klaff from his London Real interview: &quot;Just be yourself&quot; is horrible advice. You think those MMA fighters are going out there into the octagon and think &quot;I'm just gonna be myself&quot;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea behind writing and recording your life story is that it not only helps to communicate what you are about, but also forces you to clarify why you do what you do and how you can leverage the fact that only you are exactly who you are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, the wisdom of your heart might suggest otherwise: By strengthening your story you strengthen your sense of self. And that can be a hindrance. To be more clear: It will bite you in the ass sooner or later because self and identity are constructs of the mind that cause lots of pain when reality eventually cuts through them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;By explicating and narrowing down what you are about, you also put yourself in a box and give up some opportunity to change and grow beyond your self-imposed roles. That's just how the mind works. So be just yourself but know that you are everything.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;5. Trust Your Own Instinct&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So there are different sides to everything. None are right or wrong. You need to learn to listen to the deepest intuition in yourself to know what is right for you now. Dan Pena's message resonated with me when I knew deep down that what I needed most was a kick in the butt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Listen to yourself without ego. Under all those layers of adapted beliefs and other people's expectations, you will know. Follow that knowledge even against a plethora of well intended good advice. Never underestimate your gut feeling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those insights deepened through the Bizacc, which shows: &lt;b&gt;You can learn from every experience if you dare to trust the learner in the first place. You can't learn anything if you don't.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;6. Put Quality over Quantity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mentioned the inbound marketing drift of the Bizacc. Inbound marketing is the idea of regularly publishing free content online to grow leads. Therefore, the Bizacc hammered in our heads that we must put stuff out on a regular basis, whether it's blog posts, videos or what have you. The recommendation was two blog posts a week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It might just be a matter of taste, but as a reader who is quite sensitive to bad shallow writing, I came to a somewhat different conclusion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, there is also a business reason for why everyone should put quality over quantity in inbound marketing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suppose you publish only half as many blog posts as before but you invest twice as much time in the remaining posts and double their quality. That's a wash right? You produce the same amount of quality writing. Not so fast!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Engineering minds might be intrigued by the idea that everything in inbound marketing can be measured and success can be engineered. But it's a false belief. Some essentials cannot be measured.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The higher quality posts don't just convert better, they also surpass that critical threshold of amazement that gets your reader to trust you, like you, share your stuff, recommend you and most of all: come back to your site regularly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It takes lots of contact points until a visitor of your site will buy anything from you. So what good is it to engineer 10'000 clicks a month if those visitors don't even remember your site because you offer mediocre content?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My experience of making music also tells me: &lt;b&gt;Good content is inspired but also requires that you invest a lot of time in it. It comes to you easily, then you work on it hard. One well produced inspired song is worth more than a 1000 demos of formulaic compositions. People will not remember you for the latter.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;7. Do it Because You Love the Process&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there is the other and more personal reason for why I value quality over quantity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to publish on a regular basis, there's no way around publishing content that you would enjoy yourself. Otherwise, you might as well do a cubicle job and forget about integrity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I personally don't read blogs, because I think most are terribly written, lack substance and try to sell something. Even the books that come to my attention these days are marketing instruments that package hot air around an idea that's worth one sentence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So writing something I'd want to read is quite an endeavour. If I would write two blog posts a week, I'd be a full time writer. The post your're reading right now matured in the back of my head for weeks and took many sessions of structuring, writing, delineating, condensing, proof reading ...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love writing. When I work on texts, I'm in flow. And flow is all I strive for and want to give to others, hence the name of this site. Why would I give up that beautiful writing experience by cranking out trash for clicks? Sometimes we gotta ask ourselves why we're doing all this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;There is no castle on a cloud at the end of our journey where we'll live forever after we finally reached our goals. There is only our way of living, and the most we can achieve with that is to feel fulfilled here and now.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Cocoalytics Pitch</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/01/03/cocoalytics-pitch.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cocoalytics Pitch" /><published>2016-01-03T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-01-03T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2016/01/03/cocoalytics-pitch</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2016/01/03/cocoalytics-pitch.html">&lt;p&gt;
    I've been playing around with an idea for an original product called Cocoalytics. Here is my first attempt on the 1 minute pitch:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;iframe class=&quot;ft-shadow show-for-large&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/dYZx7Kflhmw&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;iframe class=&quot;ft-shadow hide-for-large&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/dYZx7Kflhmw&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    Edit on January 9: And here is the 2nd iteration:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;iframe class=&quot;ft-shadow show-for-large&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wePMiNgVF-A&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;iframe class=&quot;ft-shadow hide-for-large&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wePMiNgVF-A&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I've been playing around with an idea for an original product called Cocoalytics. Here is my first attempt on the 1 minute pitch:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tribetalk</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2015/12/24/londonreal-tribetalk-interview.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tribetalk" /><published>2015-12-24T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2015-12-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2015/12/24/londonreal-tribetalk-interview</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2015/12/24/londonreal-tribetalk-interview.html">&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/blog-images/self-development/londonreal-tribetalk-interview/poster.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; class=&quot;ft-shadow&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Two weeks ago, &lt;a href=&quot;https://londonrealacademy.com/members/noorahnaker/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Noorah&lt;/a&gt; featured me in her weekly London Real &lt;a href=&quot;https://londonrealacademy.com/tag/tribe-talk/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Tribe Talk&lt;/a&gt;. Here, I put out the &quot;director's cut&quot; of that interview with all answers as I wrote them on 08.12.2015.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    This is for all who support me on my journey and are curious about the background story of Flowtoolz.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    I thought I better get this out of the way before it gets overshadowed by the awesome things that are about to happen here. Stay tuned!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    ... Oh, in case you're not just grinding: Merry Christmas ;)
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The London Real Apple TV App&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    1) Tell us about yourself and what do you do?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    I'm an iOS app developer. However my interests are diverse: From software architecture to song writing, psychology, buddhism, paleo lifestyle, fitness and bulletproof cooking :D
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    2) How did you get involved with your latest LR Apple TV App project?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        I was still an iOS software engineer at HolidayCheck and watched the Apple keynote with my colleagues. Seeing a new Apple platform (and the iPad Pro) being announced made me restless 'cause I knew I couldn't create anything for these exciting devices at my day job.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        Then in beginning of October, I started to build a prototype for London Real, and 2 weeks later I presented the idea to Brian and Dre.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        The original presentation is still online. It became part of a blog which became part of a website.
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    3) Can you share a little more about the London Real Apple TV App and the concept behind it?
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        It was obvious to me that Londonreal.tv and Apple TV would get married at some point :) The question was: How can the app add value to London Real as soon as possible?
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        So what we're aiming at is to bring the London Real content and philosophy to people who may never have heard of London Real before. The first release will focus exclusively on streaming the latest full episodes to the living rooms around the world.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        The interface structure is clean and simple. Still it took a lot of work to customize its style and animations in order to fortify London Real as a brand.
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    4) What features can we expect to see from the London Real Apple TV App and how will it change the way we access LR?
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        So let's be honest: The app is certainly a more pleasing way to watch London Real episodes than the website. It's for the TV after all. But, as of now, its target audience are actually not hardcore London Realers who frequently visit the website anyway. The name of the game is turning casual viewers into London Realers :)
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        However, there's also a distinct new feature: If you're proud owner of a new Apple TV, you'll be able to navigate London Real episodes through an interactive table of contents. That means you can see and play the topics of an episode like songs of a music album.
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Follow Your &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TLKUFYAOoRI&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Bliss&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    5) How did you organise your work schedule around the LR project?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        Until a few days ago, this was a side project. I worked on it in the mornings and evenings and (don't tell anyone) sometimes on my job. At the end of October, I took a week off to focus on the app full time. I'm a Tim Ferriss fan, but that week was a 90 hour work week and pure bliss :D
    &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
        I realized this is ultimately the only way I want to work: deeply engaged, applying a diverse skill set, passionate about the outcome. So I quit my job.
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    6) What job were you in and why did you quit?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    I was just 5 months into a well paying job as an iOS software engineer in a great team. I quit so I could build a business and ultimately bring some of my own ideas to life.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    7) What is your core value in business and life?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        I'm a bit embarrassed 'cause I can answer that with the precision of an engineer ;)
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        My 7 core values:&lt;br&gt;
        1) Mindfulness &amp;amp; Wisdom&lt;br&gt;
        2) Self-Respect &amp;amp; Self-Esteem&lt;br&gt;
        3) Integrity &amp;amp; Authenticity&lt;br&gt;
        4) Simplicity &amp;amp; Humility&lt;br&gt;
        5) Independence &amp;amp; Freedom&lt;br&gt;
        6) Compassion &amp;amp; Dedication&lt;br&gt;
        7) Creativity &amp;amp; Productivity&lt;br&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        I could certainly go into a 3 hour discussion about what these mean to me, but I won't :D
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;London Real Academy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    8) How long have you been watching London Real for?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    Since January 2014.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    9) Why did you join the London Real Academy?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    I had been waiting for something like this since I became a fan. The specific palette of guests you host resonated deeply with me. I wanted to connect to like-minded people and be part of a great movement from its beginning.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    10) What one feature do you benefit from most in the Academy and why?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        The biggest benefit for me is my accountability buddy &lt;a href=&quot;https://londonrealacademy.com/members/jayfarei/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Gabriele&lt;/a&gt;. We take accountability quite seriously and have helped each other significantly on our journeys.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        Bringing people together who share this &quot;growth mindset&quot; is such a simple idea. But to me it's the core USP of the Academy.
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    11) How do you hold yourself accountable? Do you and Gabriele have an accountability plan?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    We basically do 3 things:&lt;br&gt;
    1) We log what we're doing every minute of each day live in a shared online spreadsheet. We also track our habits there.&lt;br&gt;
    2) We share several Trello boards, so we can observe exactly what progress the other one is making on different projects.&lt;br&gt;
    3) We catch up every Sunday on Skype. And that is definitely the most fun part :)
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Build the Best You&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    12) What experience most shapes who you are?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        Let me ignore the deep psychological dimension of the question and, instead, summarise what I learned the painful way:
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        Not doing what you love gets you nowhere. Doing everything you love at once (and timidly) gets you depressed.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        The reason I'm practicing focus and mindfulness is my wild spinning mind and its many different interests :)
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    13) What skills would you like to offer Academy members and what skills sets would you like to meet here?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        To those academy members training their idea muscles and starting IT related businesses: I will help you break down what the MVP of your mobile or TV app should be and how much effort it would take to get it published. Of course, I can build it as well ;) http://flowtoolz.com
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        I'm also looking for online marketers, backend developers and all-round talents who would do gigs for certain projects.
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    14) What advice would you offer members trying to get an app or product to the market?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    Practice letting go by focusing on one core feature that provides value to your customer. Ignore all other features. Wow, that actually sounds so simple :D
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    15) How do you cultivate knowledge from LR content and from networking with the community?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        I wrote this in a blog post: &quot;Knowledge as an abstract quality of the mind is worthless. Only as an embodied capability does it serve us.&quot;
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        If I don't see an actionable task within a bit of information, I don't do anything. But if I do, I'll create or edit the appropriate task in Trello. And trust me: Many of those tasks are inspired by London Real :)
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    16) What are your plans now?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        Right now the app has zero users, so we haven't achieved anything with it. The only thing on my mind is the release and subsequent promotion. We'll inform you about the #londonrealapp thunderclap when Apple has approved the app to go live.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        In the meantime, London Realers may read about the whole development process of the app on the blog.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        Thanks for all the encouraging feedback! I'm really joyfully overwhelmed and humbled by the support of this warm-hearted positive community :)
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Two weeks ago, Noorah featured me in her weekly London Real Tribe Talk. Here, I put out the &quot;director's cut&quot; of that interview with all answers as I wrote them on 08.12.2015. This is for all who support me on my journey and are curious about the background story of Flowtoolz. I thought I better get this out of the way before it gets overshadowed by the awesome things that are about to happen here. Stay tuned! ... Oh, in case you're not just grinding: Merry Christmas ;)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Judgement Day</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2015/12/21/judgement-day.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Judgement Day" /><published>2015-12-21T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2015-12-21T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2015/12/21/judgement-day</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2015/12/21/judgement-day.html">&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/blog-images/londonrealapp/8/poster.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; class=&quot;ft-shadow&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Last iteraton's 3 main activities regarding the London Real Apple TV app:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Fixing, fixing, fixing&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Polishing the content&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Submitting the app to Apple&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Video Wonderland&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    I encountered and solved many more small issues. But one bug was particularly tenecious and kept me wondering for days. Sometimes when jumping directly to a late chapter, playing never starts and something breaks completely in the playback system.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    It's not even a problem of our own code, which is clean as a whistle, but Apple's APIs don't provide much feedback and have their own quirks. It's not the first time I experience this. When coding the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vooxly.com&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Vooxly&lt;/a&gt; app, I already learned that the depths of Apple's media frameworks can be a wonderland.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    I improved the code around this issue, however the bug is not totally extinct yet. We have to see how much of a problem this will be for our users. Eventually, we'll need to employ Apple's http live streaming anyway. That should solve this whole class of issues.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Finishing Touches&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    We also worked on making the content bulletproof. This involved hacking our way around Vimeo bugs, updating the Vimeo playlist and polishing texts.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    We still lack some descriptions and chapters. Fortunatley, these can still be updated when the app is submitted or live.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Point of No Return&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Three days ago, we finally submitted the app to Apple for review. That was quite an intricate process which required a few days of tinkering and head scratching, but in the end we uploaded the app to iTunes Connect. Now, we're waiting for Apple to approve the app for release:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/blog-images/londonrealapp/8/itunes_connect.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; class=&quot;ft-shadow&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    I expect that &lt;i&gt;some&lt;/i&gt; issue will likely come up and we'll have to solve it and restart the approval process, so let's not get crazy until the app actually goes live :D
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    We still reached a great milestone. Even if Apple rejects this build of the app, we'll get specific feedback so our next actions would be very effective.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Process&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Until we hear from Apple, there's not much left for me to do. When the app goes live, I'll have achieved my goal and there will be time to set new goals and figure out how this story may continue.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;img width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;/blog-images/londonrealapp/8/trello.jpg&quot; class=&quot;ft-shadow&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Last iteraton's 3 main activities regarding the London Real Apple TV app: Fixing, fixing, fixing Polishing the content Submitting the app to Apple</summary></entry></feed>